

Janet Weber





jaweber64@gmail.com





28857 Rivers Edge Dr Cary, IL 60013

SUMMARY

Talented programmer known for organized, well documented code. Experience with software development process from requirements though debugging, maintenance. Expansion of skill set via recent coursework includes:

- Object oriented architecture using Java, C++, and Swift
- Design of mobile applications employing sprint/scrum features of Agile Project Management
- Web site creation using HTML and CSS, Javascript, ¡Query
- SQL database design and query

Strengths: Highly organized, quick learner, adaptable, excellent communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: C++, Java, Swift, MySQL, HTML & CSS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery, AngularJS
- Applications: Xcode, AndroidStudio, GitHub, MySQLWorkbench, Aptana Studio, Code::Blocks, Microsoft (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, OneNote), eKyros, Adobe (PhotoShop, Illustrator, InDesign)
- Operating Systems: Mac OSX, iOS, Android, Windows, Unix
- Methodologies: Agile Project Management
- Frameworks: W3Schools, Material Design Lite, Foundation

EDUCATION

McHenry County College

Crystal Lake, IL GPA: 3.9 Certificates | June 2017+ Web Dev. & Mobile Application Dev. (iOS & Android)

Villanova University

Villanova, PA
M.S. | May 1990
Computer Science
w/emphasis in
Networking

Valparaiso University

Valparaiso, IN
B.S. | May 1986
Computer Science &
Mathematics
w/Business Minor

EXPERIENCE

October 2014 - Present

Volunteer Advocate | Informed Choices | Crystal Lake, IL

Led move to digital record keeping by learning and facilitating the use of client management software among fellow advocates saving time and effort, resulting in more accurate reporting and efficient use of resources. Continue incorporation of additional software functionality.

August, 2004 - May, 2013

Teacher / Administrator | Weber Academy (home school) | Cary, IL

Taught all subjects at different grade levels concurrently to my six children through 8th grade. Evaluation of progress, testing, record keeping, curriculum review / selection.

July, 1993 - September, 1995

Technical Instructor (part-time) | NetGuru Technologies | Naperville, IL

Created and presented corporate training courses on TCP/IP and X graphics programming.

December, 1989 - July, 1993

Software Engineer | Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory (Fermilab) | Batavia, IL

Involved in entire software development process supporting various university physicists and their experiments. Mainframe / Unix workstation administration. Author of technical articles.

July, 1986 - December, 1989

Programmer | Unisys | Great Valley, PA

Software development for Department of Defense projects; Mainframe administration.